Guide to the Charles Henri Ford Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Charles Henri Ford papers
1918-2003
1928-2002
YCAL MSS 32
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
26.95
(34 boxes)
The Charles Henri Ford Papers contain correspondence, writings, and artwork that document Ford's activities as an author and journal editor,with the bulk of the material dating from 1928 to 2002. Much of the material acquired before 1982 relates to the journals Blues and View, while the 2004 acquisition includes documentation of broader range of Ford's activities.
Ford, Charles Henri, 1908-2002
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Charles Henri Ford, 1946-1949. Papers relating to the Garden of Disorder, including Ford's correspondence with George Reavey, were purchased in 1982. August 2004 Acquisition purchased from George Robert Minkoff, Inc., on the Alfred Z. Baker, Jr. Fund.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
CHARLES HENRI FORD (1913-2002 )
The American surrealist, Charles Henri Ford, was an influential writer and an editor. In 1933 he published The Young and the Evil, a novel he wrote with Parker Tyler. He is better known, however, for his collections of surrealist poetry, including The Garden of Disorder (1939) and The Overturned Lake (1941), and for editing the surrealist magazines Blues and View. He published Blues from 1929 to 1930 while he was still a teenager. View ran from 1940 to 1947 and contained works of young artists and poets including Joseph Cornell, Randall Jarrell, and Allen Ginsberg.
Ford was born in Hazlehurst, Mississippi, on February 10, 1913 to Charles Lloyd and Gertrude Cato Ford. He attended the Christian Brothers College Grammar School in Memphis, Tennessee, where he lived with his mother and sister Ruth. In 1922 he was sent away to the Webb School in Bellbuckle, Tennessee, and later attended the Morgan School in St. Petersburg, Tennessee. In 1929, he went to St. Mary's University in San Antonio, Texas, for at least one semester.
Later in 1929, Ford lived in both Columbus, Mississippi, and New York City, while he edited Blues. In 1930 he moved to Paris, where he lived for four years. During this period he developed friendships with several literary figures, among whom were Gertrude Stein and Djuna Barnes. After traveling through Europe and North Africa, Ford returned to New York in October, 1934.
Following his return, Ford concentrated on writing poetry and editing View. Poems for Painters was published by View Editions in 1945, followed by The Half-Thoughts in 1947 and Sleep in a Nest of Flames in 1949, which included a foreword by Edith Sitwell. He also edited The Mirror of Baudelaire in 1942 and A Night with Jupiter and Other Fantastic Stories in 1947. The book of stories was a View edition and included two pieces by Henry Miller. His later collections of verse include Spare Parts (1966), Silver Flower Coo (1968), Om Krishna (1978), and Secret Haiku (1982). His selected poems, Flag of Ecstasy, edited by Edward B. Germain, was published in 1972.
Arrangement
Organized into two groupings: 1946-1982 Acquisitions, and August 2004 Acquisition.
Scope and Contents
The Charles Henri Ford Papers contain correspondence, writings, and artwork that document Ford's activities as an author and journal editor, with the bulk of the material dating from 1928 to 2002. Much of the material acquired before 1982 relates to the journals Blues and View, while the 2004 Acquisition includes documentation of broader range of Ford's activities. Personal and professional correspondence documents Ford's relationships with family members as well as American authors and artistic figures including Parker Tyler. Notebooks and diaries contain drafts of writings and personal observations. Art Files document Ford's creative process of producing collages, and include source material containing clippings and other images. Personal papers document medical, legal, and financial aspects of Ford's life. Unsorted Papers consist of material retained by Ford for his archive, grouped roughly chronologically, but otherwise unarranged.
Art, Modern -- 20th Century; Artists -- United States; Authors, American; Editors -- United States; Little magazines; Magazine illustration -- 20th Century; Modernism (Art); Modernism (Literature); Painting, Modern -- 20th Century; Poetry, Modern -- 20th Century; Poets, American -- 20th Century; Surrealism; Drawings (visual works) -- United States -- 20th Century; Illustrations (layout features) -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Scrapbooks -- United States -- 20th Century; Artists -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Editors -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Bentley, Eric, 1916-; Ford, Charles Henri, 1908-2002; Genet, Jean, 1910-1986; Mariën, Marcel, 1920-1993; Miller, Henry, 1891-1980; Reavey, George, 1907-1976; Reynolds, Mary; Serbanne, Claude; Tyler, Parker, 1904-1974; Williams, William Carlos, 1883-1963; Young, Kathleen Tankersley, d. 1963
- 1946-1982 Acquisitions, 1928-1947; 5; (7 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into three series: I. Correspondence, 1928-1947. II. Writings, 1937. III. Journal Editing, 1941-1947.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Charles Henri Ford, 1946-1949. Papers relating to the Garden of Disorder, including Ford's correspondence with George Reavey, were purchased in 1982.
  - Correspondence, 1928-1947; Series I; 1; (2 boxes)
    Arranged alphabetically. Unidentified correspondence is filed at the end of the series.
    Scope and Contents
    Series I, Correspondence (Boxes 1-2), consists of letters received by Ford as editor of Blues (1929-30) and later as editor of View (1940-47), as well as both sides of his correspondence with George Reavey. Reavey published The Garden of Disorder in 1938, and their letters concern the technical production of the book of poems, including the cover drawing by Pavel Tchelitchew. William Carlos Williams contributed an introduction. In his twenty-five letters he often gave Ford technical advice. In one March 25, 1937 letter Williams says, "my old obsessions coming up again: compression, tautology, omission of the unnecessary word--cut, cut, cut--explain nothing."
    Williams also served as a contributing editor of Blues with Kathleen Tankersley Young, Joseph Vogel and Eugene Jolas. In his February 5, 1929 letter, Vogel quotes Ezra Pound's praise of Blues: "Pound was right when he said that Blues is biggest thing since Little Review ." Young's fifty letters are more personal. They describe Joe Gould's sexual advances, for example, when Young tried to get his manuscripts for Blues. Eugene Jolas recommended Whit Burnett's poetry for Blues and thanked Ford for his contributions of photography and poetry to Transition.
    Blues helped launch many writing careers, including Ford's. In 1930, for example, H. L. Mencken solicited Ford's poetry for The American Mercury. Other contributors to Blues included Djuna Barnes and Kenneth Rexroth, who sent biographical information in his March 15, 1929 letter. Ezra Pound gave Ford advice on how to run a "young " magazine and urged him to get a "summary of the Brancusi case" (Box 2, folder 144). H.D. thought her poems in number six "were beautifully set up" (Box 1, folder 77). Erskine Caldwell wrote one of his letters in the form of a spiral and later, in April 1930, explained that he was trying "to do some work that would have more than four teats of consumptive milch." Kay Boyle thanked Ford for his favorable reviews and continued writing until 1946 about living in Nice next to Alfred Kreymborg and arranging a show for Wols with Marcel Duchamp.
    Other authors were not impressed with Ford or Blues. Marsden Hartley wrote that " Blues reveals nothing in the way of new rhythms... and it seems to me to be as old as the hills" (Box 1, folder 80), while Laura Riding Jackson blasted Ford at the end of her correspondence: "You have treated me not as a work that caused you satisfaction or botherance but as a woman with whom you were having sexuo-literary intercourse" (Box 1, folder 87).
    The responses to View were just as varied. Lincoln Kirstein praised the magazine, but on March 15, 1946 Philip Lamantia asked to have his name taken off the masthead, saying View was a symbol of the "perverted sensibility of our time" and Ford was in "direct relationship with everything that accounts for the basic corruption of this generation."
    The bulk of Ford's correspondents wrote fewer than five letters except for his Paris agent, Mary Reynolds, who sent him photographs of French exhibitions; Eric Bentley, who wrote American theater reviews; and Henry Miller, who contributed short stories and complained about not getting paid for his reviews. Many of Ford's correspondents wrote from different countries. Marcel Mariën wrote about the surrealists in Belgium, Edouard Roditi about surrealism in Germany, Asger Jorn about art in Denmark, and Claude Serbanne about France. Serbanne's letters are in French, as are many others in the collection. Artists also wrote from England, Spain, Mexico, Cuba, and A. Mezei asked Ford in 1947 for back issues of View to help his artist friends in Budapest understand the modernist movement.
    Many prominent artists wrote to Ford thanking him for promoting them in View, such as Jean Dubuffet and Joan Miró. Dimitri Petrov thanked him for organizing his exhibition at the View Gallery, and Marcel Duchamp telegrammed to suggest doing a special issue of the magazine devoted to French surrealism. Other artists contributed cover designs, such as Esteban Francés, Jean Hélion, John Tunnard, and Wifredo Lam. The photographer, Thomas Dyce, sent him "Gonzoprints," Marc Chagall invited him to his opening at the Museum of Modern Art, and Henri Cartier-Bresson asked him to see his film "Le Retour" at the Metropolitan Museum. René Magritte contributed drawings to View, including "Le Puritan" attached to his July 1, 1946 letter. Lesser known illustrators like Dudley Huppler and Neal Thomas sent him material and were often surprised when Ford used it without their permission.
    Many prominent writers also contributed to View. Edith Sitwell sent her poetry, and Mina Loy asked Ford to attach a note about Marcel Duchamp to her poem "The Blind Boy." Baronesse Blixen refused to send material in 1945 because she could get "twice the amount for a story here in Denmark or Sweden, and it is easier for me to write in Danish than in English." Vladimir Nabokov was insulted by Ford's absurd offer to pay five dollars per review, and Edouard Roditi, who translated André Breton and did book reviews, complained to Ford that "you rarely pay unless reminded" (Box 2, folder 160). Similarly, Jean Genet's lengthy correspondence with Ford concerned money. Ford wanted to bring out a View edition of Notre Dame des Fleurs, but failed to raise Genet's $500 fee.
    Ford also encouraged unknown writers. His correspondence is filled with letters from young poets like Russell Atkins from Cleveland, Ohio, Ray Edwards from England, and the black poet, Joe Massey, who wrote from his prison cell in Cleveland, Ohio. Ford also received many unsolicited manuscripts. A doctor of astro-psychiatry, for example, sent him the work of his patient, Jason Gordon, "a twenty-six year old Louisiana Negro" (Box 1, folder 56).
    Other magazine editors and publishers contributed material to View in exchange for free ads and articles. On May 26, 1946 Wolfgang Cordan asked to reprint Zadkine's essay on Minotaur in his Dutch publication and assured Ford that in number VIII of Centaur "you will find an essay on your poetry." Similar agreements were made with Dennis Dobson, the English editor of Focus; with Christian Cotremont of the French magazine Sélection; and with Jean de Venke, editor of Solstice in Belgium. José Garcia Villa sent him Edith Sitwell's poems when a special issue of Viva was postponed. Luis J. Navascués, the editor of Ambos Mundos, requested a transcript of Jean Paul Sartre's lecture that Ford organized in 1946. Kerker Quinn of Accent asked for View 's subscription list. Ford traded advertisement space with the publisher, James Laughlin, after being reprimanded: "You take something that doesn't belong to you--the Miller story--then try to blackmail me into letting you get away with it" (Box 1, folder 101).
    The rest of the correspondence is from scholars like Ann Balakian requesting information about André Breton, from writers like Robert Horan asking permission to reprint his poems, and from friends like Leonor Fini, who sent personal notes and poems on decorative French paper. Ford's responses and those of his staff are often written in the margins. "J. P." added a note to the bottom of Wallace Stevens's brief cover letter, for example, saying: "He still sounds very pretty with a maximum of provincial (uprooted cosmopolitan) chic."
    - Aiken, Conrad, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alexander, Lloyd (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Anderson, Forrest, 1934 Nov 21 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Andrews, Wayne, 1943-46 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Anthony, George, 1946 Jan 8 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Armistead, Horace, 1945 Aug 7 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Atkins, Russell, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Balakian, Ann, 1947 Jan 6 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Baradinsky, Oscar, 1946 Aug 12 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Barnes, Djuna, 1930-47 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Barrett, William, 1946 Jan 19 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bentley, Eric, 1945-47, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Berman, Eugene, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Biederman, Charles, 1946 Apr 27 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Blackshear, Kathleen, 1943 Mar 15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Blixen, Karen, 1945 Oct 22 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bourcier, Claude L., 1943 Apr 21 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bowles, Paul, 1946, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Boyle, Kay, 1929-46 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Brecht, Bertold, 1947 Apr 29 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Brice, Germain, 1945-46 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Brown, Carlyle S., 1943 Mar 5 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Bryan, William, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Bulyn(?), Funi, 1944-46 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Burke, Kenneth, 1946 Mar 30 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Caffeen, Mary, 1947 Apr 8 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Calas, Nic, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Caldwell, Erskine, 1929-30 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Cantrell, Leon, 1946 Oct 4 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Carlson, Luella H., 1946 Aug 28 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Carrington, Leonora, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Cartier-Bresson, Henri, 1946, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Chagall, Marc, 1946, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Chiaromonte, Nicola, 1945 Jan 18 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Childs, Paul, 1945-46 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Cocteau, Jean, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Colinet, Paul, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Connolly, Cyril, 1945 Dec 27 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Cordan, Wolfgang, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Cornell, Joseph, 1947 Apr 9 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Coutaud, Lucien, 1946 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Criel, Gaston, 1946 Jan 23 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Crosby, Harry, 1929, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Davis, Halsey, 1943 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - De Rougemont, Denis, 1945 Dec 25 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Decker, James, 1945 Dec 29 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Demarest, Andrew, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Dobson, Dennis, 1946 Jan 9 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Dotremont, Christian, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Downer, Alan S., 1946 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Dryce, Thomas Harvey, 1946, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Dubuffet, Jean, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Duchamp, Marcel, 1947 Aug 4 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Duncan, Otis Dudley, 1946 Jan 14 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Durrell, Lawrence, 1946, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Ebennon, Trafiel, 1946 Oct 2 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Edwards, Ray, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Eternelle Revue, 1946 Feb 11 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Faro, R. Vale, 1946 Nov 4 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Farrar, Straus and Company, Inc., 1946 Apr 19 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Ferguson, Francis, 1947, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Ferry, Jean, 1946 Jan 15 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Fini, Leonor, 1946, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Foley, Martha, 1945 Jun 28 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Fowlie, Wallace, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Foy, Gray, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Francés, Esteban, 1945-46 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Freedom, 1947 Jul 29 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Genet, Jean, 1945-46, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Gheerbrant, Alain, 1946 Feb-Mar (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Giovanelli, Felix, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Girodias, M., 1946 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Goldman, Elliott, 1946 Aug 3 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Goll, Yvan, 1945 Sep 2 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Graham, W. S., 1945 Jun 6 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Gregory, Horace, 1929 Mar 13 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - H.D. (Hilda Doolittle), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Haller, Paula, 1945 Apr 12 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Hamilton, George Heard, 1945 Feb 5 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Hartley, Marsden, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Hays, H. R., 1946 Apr 2 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Hélion, Jean, 1946, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Hitchcock, Henry Russell, 1945-46 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Horan, Robert, 1947 Oct 1 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Hoyningen-Huene, George, 1947 Apr 15 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Huppler, Dudley, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Jackson, Laura Riding, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Jaguer, Edouard, 1946 Mar 26 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Jewell, Edward A., 1945 Mar 8 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Jolas, Eugene, 1929 Dec 30 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Jorn, Asger, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Kamin, Sally, 1946 Mar 8 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Kamp, Jerry, 1943 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Kanters, Robert, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Kelly, Leon, 1945-47 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Kirstein, Lincoln, n.y. Mar 19 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Krozser, Stephen J., 1946 Jun 3 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Lam, Wifredo, 1945-47 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Lamantia, Philip, 1946 Mar 15 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Landberg, Edward, 1946 Oct (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Laughlin, James, 1945, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - Leite, George, 1945 Jan 28 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Leyda, Jay, 1930 Oct 28 (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - Liebenson, Gloria, 1946 Dec 12 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - Lindsay, Jack, 1946, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - Lipchitz, Jacques, 1945 Sep 20 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - Lisan, S., 1946 Oct 8 (Box 1, Folder 107)
    - Loy, Mina, 1945 Feb 1 (Box 1, Folder 108)
    - Lynes, George Platt, 1942 Apr 20 (Box 1, Folder 109)
    - McCarthy, Mary, 1946, n.d (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Machado, Mary, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - McLuhan, Marshall, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - McNeil, John, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - Magriel, Paul, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Magritte, René, 1946 Jul 1 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Malaquais, Jean, 1947 Jan 15 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Mandiargues, Andri Pieyre de, 1947 Feb 4 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Mariën, Marcel, 1946-47 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Mascolo, Dionys, 1945 Jan 28 (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Massey, Joe, 1946-47 (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Masson, André, 1945 Jul 19 (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - Mellers, Wilfred, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Melville, Robert, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - Mencken, H. L., 1930 Oct 31 (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - Merriam, Harold A., 1947, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 125)
    - Merrild, Knud, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 126)
    - Mezei, A., 1947 Jan 27 (Box 2, Folder 127)
    - Middleton, Christopher, 1947 Feb 22 (Box 2, Folder 128)
    - Milano, Pablo, 1945 Sep 25 (Box 2, Folder 129)
    - Miller, Henry, 1945-46, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 130)
    - Miró, Jean, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 131)
    - Moore, Marianne, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 132)
    - Morse, Rose, 1945 May 7 (Box 2, Folder 133)
    - Nabokov, Vladimir, 1946 Mar (Box 2, Folder 134)
    - Naene, Lowell, 1946 Sep (Box 2, Folder 135)
    - Navascués, Luis J., 1946 Jan-Mar (Box 2, Folder 136)
    - New York Public Library, 1947 Jul 25 (Box 2, Folder 137)
    - Paggioli, Renato, 1946 Jul 19 (Box 2, Folder 138)
    - Partch, Virgil, 1946 Feb (Box 2, Folder 139)
    - Paulhan, Jean, 1946-47 (Box 2, Folder 140)
    - Perry, Clay, 1945 Sep 26 (Box 2, Folder 141)
    - Petrov, Dimitri, 1946, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 142)
    - Poch, Leo, 1942-45 (Box 2, Folder 143)
    - Pound, Ezra, 1929-30, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 144)
    - Powys, John C., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 145)
    - Quinn, Kerker, 1944 Dec 14 (Box 2, Folder 146)
    - Ray, Man, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 147)
    - Read, Bill, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 148)
    - Read, Herbert, 1946, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 149)
    - Reavey, George, 1937-39, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 150-52)
    - Reinhardt, Siegfried, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 153)
    - Renne, René, 1945-47 (Box 2, Folder 154)
    - Renzio, Tonidel, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 155)
    - Revista de Guatemala, 1946 Dec 25 (Box 2, Folder 156)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth, 1929-31, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 157)
    - Reynolds Mary, 1945-47 (Box 2, Folder 158)
    - Richards, V
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Box 1, folder 68
    - Richards, William C., 1943 Apr 7 (Box 2, Folder 159)
    - Roditi, Edouard, 1945-46, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 160)
    - Sartre, Jean Paul, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 161)
    - Schapiro, Meyer, 1944-45 (Box 2, Folder 162)
    - Seligmann, Kurt, 1945, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 163)
    - Sender, Ramón, 1945-47, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 164)
    - Serbanne, Claude, 1945-46, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 165)
    - Shattuck, Charles, 1947 Apr 8 (Box 2, Folder 166)
    - Sitwell, Edith, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 167)
    - Soby, James T., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 168)
    - Specter, Herman, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 169)
    - Stevens, Wallace, 1945 Aug 20 (Box 2, Folder 170)
    - Tanguy, Yves, 1946, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 171)
    - Tanning, Dorothea, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 172)
    - Tavernier, René, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 173)
    - Thomas, Neal, 1946, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 174)
    - Tunnard, John, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 175)
    - Tyler, Parker, 1929-31, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 176)
    - Ubac, Raoul, 1945, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 177)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1945 Oct 31 (Box 2, Folder 178)
    - Ver Duft, Gent, 1944 Nov 15 (Box 2, Folder 179)
    - Vesey, Desmond, 1947 Apr 14 (Box 2, Folder 180)
    - Veubeke, Jean de, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 181)
    - Viereck, Peter, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 182)
    - Villa, José Garcia, 1947 Mar-Apr (Box 2, Folder 183)
    - Vogel, Joseph, 1929, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 184)
    - Voices, 1945 Oct 20 (Box 2, Folder 185)
    - Wallis, Eleanor, 1945 Jan 14 (Box 2, Folder 186)
    - Walter, E., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 187)
    - Willard, Bevelyn L., 1946 Sep 13 (Box 2, Folder 188)
    - Williams, William Carlos, 1929-44, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 189)
    - Wilson, U. Adrian, 1946 May 24 (Box 2, Folder 190)
    - Wind, Edgar, 1946 Mar 20 (Box 2, Folder 191)
    - Windham, Donald, 1945 Dec 5 (Box 2, Folder 192)
    - Wolff, Kurt H., 1945 Jul 14 (Box 2, Folder 193)
    - Young, Kathleen Tankersley, 1928-31 (Box 2, Folder 194-95)
    - Young, Stark, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 196)
    - Zadkine, Ossip, 1945, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 197)
    - Zlenei, Faluzio, 1946 May 4 (Box 2, Folder 198)
    - Zondervan, Richard, 1946 May 13 (Box 2, Folder 199)
    - Unidentified, 1945-46, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 200)
  - Writings, 1937; Series II; 0.25; (1 box)
    Organized into two subseries: Books and Poetry. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically by title.